

ABOUT

Experienced analytics professional with a passion for data and technology. In my current role I focus on effectively sourcing, processing, and visualizing data in order to provide insight and actionable intelligence. In my free time I am working on learning more data science tools to expand my current skillset and broaden my knowledge of the field.

EDUCATION

University of Pittsburgh
Bachelor of Science - Business
Administration
Triple Major: Business Information
Systems, Supply Chain Management
Marketing

SKILLS

Tableau Oracle Analytics Cloud

Alteryx (OACs)

Python Oracle Transactional SQL Business Intelligence

VBA (OTBI)

Power BI Google Analytics

Excel Google Tag Manager

CERTIFICATIONS

Tableau Desktop Certified Associate Alteryx Designer Core Certification Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

Please visit my website https://tpoluch.github.io/# (QR code below) for a more thorough understanding of my work and experience



WORK EXPERIENCE

AWS, Business Intelligence Analyst

October 2022 - Present

- Answered strategic business questions and provide actionable intelligence through the design and creation of data pipelines using SQL, Tableau Prep, etc. to generate dataset which I used to create visualizations providing an easy way to digest and understand the data
- Tools: DataGrip, SQL, PyCharm, python, Tableau, Tableau Prep,

Highmark Health, Senior Business Intelligence Analyst May 2022 - October 2022

- Assisted in the implementation of Oracle Analytics Cloud by setting up and defining the contents of its data housed in the ADW
- Became a SME in Oracle Analytics Cloud and helped define and build new data sources to be used in the tool
- Built management dashboards providing insight into financial operations
- Tools: Oracle Analytics Cloud, Oracle OTBI, Excel, Alteryx, PowerBI

Highmark Health, Senior Data Reporting Analyst

June 2021 - May 2022

- Assisted in the implementation of Oracle ERP by setting up its reporting tool and provided training and support to end users
- Lead the adoption effort of the Oracle Analytics Cloud and built out ETL processes to source and visualize data used by leadership
- Tools: Oracle OTBI, Oracle Analytics Cloud, Excel, PowerBI

Highmark Health, Data Reporting Analyst

June 2020 - June 2021

- Use Tableau as a front-end BI tool and Alteryx as a back end data sourcing, processing, and automation tool to design and develop workflows, dashboards, and self-service data
- Tools: Tableau, Alteryx, Python, Excel

Highmark Health, Emerging Leaders Program Associate *June 2018 - June 2020*

Rotational program consisting of four 6-month rotations in various data analyst roles

- Developed and automated data sourcing, cleaning, and processing infrastructure using Alteryx and Toad for Oracle for team's data needs
- Developed Tableau dashboards visualizing resource forecasted time data, resource availability, resource skills data, and financial and utilization data
- Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Toad, Power BI, SQL, Excel, VBA, Cognos